We are all aware of the effect greenhouse gas emissions is having on our planet and the efforts needed to tackle climate change.
我们都清楚温室气体排放对地球造成的影响，也明白应对气候变化需要付出怎样的努力。
Most of us are doing our bit to minimise our impact on the environment, but despite our collective effort, are we doing enough to achieve net zero by 2050?
大多数人都在尽自己的一份力，减少对环境的影响，但即便我们共同努力，要在2050年实现净零排放目标，我们目前所做的真的足够吗？
Net zero means not adding to the amount of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere.
净零排放是指不再向大气中新增温室气体。
Many countries are doing their bit by changing how they generate and use power, thereby cutting carbon dioxide output.
许多国家正通过改变能源的生产和使用方式来尽一份力，从而减少二氧化碳的排放量。
And they announced what further steps they were going to take at the recent COP26 summit in Glasgow.
在最近于格拉斯哥举办的第26届联合国气候变化大会上，各国公布了后续将要采取的举措。
In the UK, the government has been setting out its plans to achieve net zero by 2050.
英国政府已出台了2050年实现净零排放的相关计划。
It’s recently announced an end date for the sale of gas boilers, which are used for heating homes. The idea is to replace them with heat pumps. It’s offering homeowners grants of up to £5,000 to get them installed.
该国近期宣布了家用燃气锅炉的截止销售时间，计划用热泵取而代之，同时还向房主提供最高5000英镑的补贴，用于安装热泵。
Another initiative in the UK is a big push towards electric vehicles. There are to be financial incentives for car manufacturers, and more charging points are to be installed in streets. And there’s to be a ban on the sale of new petrol and diesel cars by 2030.
英国的另一项举措是大力推广电动汽车，不仅为汽车制造商提供财务补贴，还将在街道上增设更多充电桩，并且计划在2030年起禁止销售新的汽油车和柴油车。
But not all emissions can be reduced to zero, so those remaining will have to be compensated for, or offset.
但并非所有排放都能降至零，因此剩余的排放量必须通过抵消手段来处理。
One way to do this is to plant thousands of trees, which are good at absorbing carbon dioxide.
其中一种方法是大规模植树造林，树木善于吸收二氧化碳。
The UK government has pledged to plant 30,000 hectares of trees a year by 2025.
英国政府承诺，到2025年每年将植树3万公顷。
There are other ideas too, but what’s certain is this will cost money.
当然还有其他的减排思路，但可以肯定的是，实现净零排放需要投入大量资金。
The CBI’s Tom Thackray told the BBC that “those costs have to be weighed up against the cost of inaction.”
英国工业联合会的汤姆·撒克雷在接受BBC采访时表示：“我们必须权衡这些投入与不作为所付出的代价。”
Whether the UK, or anyone else, reaches net zero remains to be seen.
英国或其他任何国家能否如期实现净零排放，尚有待观察。
And there’s some doubt about how this can be accurately measured anyway.
此外，关于如何准确测算净零排放，目前也存在一些争议。
But it’s generally recognised that a global effort is needed to tackle climate change.
但人们普遍认为，应对气候变化需要全球共同努力。
Therefore, net zero targets only make sense if every other country is moving in the same direction.
因此，只有当所有国家都朝着同一个方向迈进时，净零排放目标才有实际意义。